Roger Pender III

San Marcos, CA | rdpender3@gmail.com | LinkedIn | rogerpender.com

SUMMARY

Experienced full-stack developer with a passion for crafting tailored solutions from concept to implementation. Adept at both independent and collaborative problem solving, with a focus on driving client success. Committed to continuous improvement in technical expertise, coding skills, and staying current with the latest industry tools and trends.

SKILLS

React, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Node, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Express, Wordpress, PHP, Next JS, Vite, Pardot, Addsearch, Salesforce.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, Electric & Gas Industries Association | Sacramento, CA

Jul 2019 - Current

- Maintain EGIA and partner company websites
- Create custom web pages using HTML, CSS, PHP, and Javascript
- Collaborate with designers to turn mockups into functional pages
- Communicate with developers from other companies to add functionality and features to our sites
- Manage EGIA's searchable database, update DNS records, and provide technical support to sales teams and users

Teaching Assistant, UC Berkeley Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Sep 2019 – Mar 2020

- Collaborated with instructors during class and conducted review sessions to solidify concepts with students
- Taught the basics of programming including HTML5, CSS and Javascript, followed by frameworks and libraries such as React, NodeJs, and ExpressJs
- Conveyed complex technical information in an understandable and effective manner
- Graded weekly assignments and provided feedback on bugs or redundant code

Student Mentor, UC Davis Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp

Oct 2018 – May 2019

 Assisted students with coding issues by guiding them through paired programming. Worked both in-person and remotely.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Springboard | Online | Mar 2024 - Current Software Engineer Certificate (In Progress)

University of California Davis | Davis, CA | Mar 2018 - Nov 2019 Full Stack Web Development Certificate

University of California Davis | Davis, CA | Aug 2010 - May 2014 Bachelor of Science, Animal Biology